

Anushree Bagchi 🔀 in

Self taught & passionate Frontend Engineer with around 3+ years of Frontend experience building highly data driven frontends with complex state management. I have knowledge of React, Redux, Polymer Js etc.

Contact - anushreebagchi4791@gmail.com | +91 9972653424 I am relocating to London in September . I would *not* need any work VISA sponsorship.

Links

- Github I have a fairly active Github profile where I routinely build small personal projects to pick up new skills
- Portfolio More about my work and hobby projects.

Key Points

- Experience working on frontend which are data driven and have a lot of complex workflows.
- I help build Riversand's main SAAS offering Master Data Management portal using Polymer JS which B2B users use to manage the huge amount of data for day to day business.
- To help manage the huge frontend code, I had introduced Redux to my current company for managing the state of the app in a maintainable and extensible way
- I have knowledge of React, Polymer JS, Knockout JS and JQuery. I feel at home, both with frameworks as well as vanilla Javascript

Work Experience

Riversand Technologies, UI Developer, Feb 2019 ~ Present

I worked on Riversand's main SAAS offering. The product is a B2B platform for Master Data Management.

riversand

- The product stood out in its ability to manage large amounts of data and support for multiple data related workflows.
- I worked on Polymer to build the highly interactive and data driven frontend.
- I Introduced Redux to the product for streamlining and decoupling the state management.

Altisource Technology, Software Engineer (Frontend), Dec 2017 ~ Feb 2019



I started off as a self-taught JavaScript Developer. User interfaces always fascinated me and even before moving to the new role, I started picking up skills on Front End. Altisource recognized my passion and moved me into this role.

 As a part of this role I worked on Trelix which was a cloud based product used for Mortgage Fulfillment Services.

- I worked on Knockout JS and JQuery to build out the interactive interfaces of the Trelix portal
- Altisource Technology, Software Engineer (QA), Sep 2013 ~ Dec 2017



As someone who was responsible for Quality of our business Critical Banking application called Trelix, I had to think of ways to break the product. I picked up a combination of skills while in the role like Selenium testing, java, etc. Towards the end , I picked up Katalon where I learned groovy.

Education

Udacity, Nanodegree Program, Algorithms and Data Structures, 2020

Learned different data structures that can be used to store data. Implemented different methods used to manipulate these data structures and examine the efficiency. Learned the advantages and applications of different data structures. Learned how to approach open ended problems and select appropriate data structures based on requirements.

Udacity, Nanodegree Program, Frontend Developer, 2018

As a part of the Nano-degree I have made various Javascript projects that you can see here - http://anushree.tech/. My primary focus was to shift from a QA role to a Frontend role . I picked up skills like HTML 5 , CSS , Javascript Design patterns, JQuery, etc.

Chhattisgarh Swami Vivekanand Technical University, Bhilai, Bachelor's Degree, Bachelor of Engineering (BE), 2008 ~ 2012

Bachelor's in Electronics, primarily focussed on Microcontrollers, VLSI and Control Systems.